<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Chris Amico, journalist &amp; programmer: Links</title><link>https://chrisamico.com</link><description>Journalist &amp; programmer</description><atom:link href="https://chrisamico.com" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:25:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pork-pocalypse now? In wake of Supreme Court ruling and 2016 vote, pork prices could soar in Mass. - The Boston Globe</title><link>https://www.bostonglobe.com/2023/05/27/business/pork-pocalypse-now-wake-supreme-court-ruling-2016-vote-pork-prices-could-soar-mass/</link><description>A 2016 animal welfare ballot measure that would prohibit most US pork from being sold in Massachusetts could finally take effect as soon as next month. And pork purveyors here say that means prices are about to pop.</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 23:23:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From the editor: Sonoma County trans student-athlete’s story is not ours to tell</title><link>https://www.pressdemocrat.com/article/news/from-the-editor-sonoma-county-trans-student-athletes-story-is-not-ours-to/</link><description>The national firestorm that ignited last week over a Sonoma County transgender student-athlete is bullying, plain and simple, says Richard A. Green, executive editor of The Press Democrat.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 20:12:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As wildfire smoke worsens public health, government watchdog calls EPA response 'ad hoc'</title><link>https://www.muckrock.com/news/archives/2023/may/23/wildfire-smoke-exceptional-event/</link><description>Congressional investigators say the use of a regulatory loophole to erase smoke pollution from the official record is on the rise.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 14:14:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gannett is experiencing a mass exodus among top execs. Here’s who has left. - Poynter</title><link>https://www.poynter.org/business-work/2023/gannett-is-experiencing-a-mass-exodus-among-top-execs-heres-who-has-left/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 12:54:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eat more beans. Please.</title><link>https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/5/12/23717519/beans-protein-nutrition-sustainability-climate-food-security-solution-vegan-alternative-meat</link><description>Beans are high in protein, efficient to grow, and can even improve soil health. They cost less than conventional or new plant-based meats, and they’re increasingly getting attention among foodies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 19:33:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unpacking the Myths of Drilling in MMA, BJJ, and Kickboxing: Understanding Ecological Dynamics</title><link>https://www.primalmke.com/blogs/news/unpacking-the-myths-of-drilling-in-mma-bjj-and-kickboxing-understanding-ecological-dynamics</link><description>









The world of martial arts has been long dominated by the belief that repetitive drilling leads to perfected techniques and muscle memory. However, this conventional wisdom is often contradicted by research and practices in the dynamic and complex sports of MMA, BJJ, and Kickboxing. In this article, we'll delve into the key myths surrounding drilling and explore the ecological dynamics that shape the way we learn and perform in these sports.
Muscle Memory: Separating Fact from Fiction
The term </description><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 03:39:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s Tennis vs. Pickleball vs. Padel. Or Is It?</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/11/sports/tennis/pickleball-platform-tennis-padel.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 23:36:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What the end of the COVID public health emergency means in Massachusetts</title><link>https://www.wbur.org/news/2023/05/09/covid-public-health-emergency-ending-massachusetts-vaccine-mandate-masks-newsletter</link><description>After more than three years, COVID public health emergencies at the federal level and in Massachusetts come to an end Thursday. Here's what will change with testing, masking, vaccination and more.</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 23:21:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>God Emperor of Dune would make a terrible movie — and we need it</title><link>https://www.polygon.com/23716984/god-emperor-of-dune-movie-adaptation-denis-villeneuve</link><description>C’mon, Denis Villeneuve, give us our giant philosophical worm king</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 01:59:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Same Work but a Lot Less Pay for Women. Welcome to Tennis in 2023.</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/10/sports/tennis/women-men-prize-money.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 12:35:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Life Expectancy and Inequality</title><link>https://medium.com/analytics-vidhya/life-expectancy-and-inequality-7eb4d58617b8</link><description>America is experiencing the greatest gap in life expectancy across regions in the last 40 years</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 15:45:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opinion | Pickleball is the worst</title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/05/08/pickleball-hate-reasons/</link><description>Any game you can take up after breakfast and be pretty good at by lunch is not a sport. And it isn't even great exercise. </description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 19:24:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Analysis | America’s learned helplessness on guns</title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2023/05/08/texas-shooting-mental-health-republicans-abbott/</link><description>The debate over how to address gun violence is between doing something and doing nothing.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 19:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electrify everything (in my house)</title><link>https://buttondown.email/theplanetyousave/archive/electrify-everything-in-my-house-a-qa-with-laura/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 15:51:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Analysis | The low cost (for a rich person) of sponsoring a Supreme Court justice</title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2023/05/04/clarence-thomas-supreme-court-harlan-crow/</link><description>America's wealth gap makes it trivial for billionaires to cover whoever's bills they want.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 15:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How open content is transforming American journalism</title><link>https://werd.io/2023/how-open-content-is-transforming-american-journalism</link><description>I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on the intersection of technology, media, and democracy. Subscribe by email to get every update.&#13;
It&amp;rsquo;s genuinely refreshing to see how non-profit newsrooms have</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 14:35:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>“Alexa Will Not Replace Us”</title><link>https://amazonchronicles.ghost.io/alexa-will-not-replace-us/</link><description>The Writers Guild of America is on strike, bringing movie and television production to a halt. This affects media companies across the board, but one of them is Amazon, which is not exactly like other media companies. It's primarily a retailer as well as a technology and infrastructure company. However,</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 20:29:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Dune: Part Two’—An Exclusive First Look at the Saga’s Epic Conclusion</title><link>https://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2023/04/dune-part-two-exclusive-first-look</link><description>Timothée Chalamet, Zendaya, and director Denis Villeneuve share secrets from the new film and reveal Florence Pugh’s, Austin Butler’s, and Léa Seydoux’s new characters.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 23:35:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China’s sweeping new anti-espionage law will make it easier to arrest foreigners</title><link>https://www.theglobeandmail.com/world/article-chinas-sweeping-new-anti-espionage-law-will-make-it-easier-to-arrest/</link><description>New law expands the definition of spying amid a renewed crackdown on journalists and growing pressure on foreign businesses</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 13:47:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Disney is shrinking FiveThirtyEight, and Nate Silver (and his models) are leaving</title><link>https://www.niemanlab.org/2023/04/disney-is-shrinking-fivethirtyeight-and-nate-silver-and-his-models-are-leaving/</link><description>Silver on ABC: "They have limited rights to some models post–license term, but not the core election forecast stuff."</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 20:28:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>