<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Chris Amico, journalist &amp; programmer: Links</title><link>https://chrisamico.com</link><description>Journalist &amp; programmer</description><atom:link href="https://chrisamico.com" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 18:11:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Great Newspapers and the Problem of Underspending Billionaires</title><link>https://open.substack.com/pub/dicktofel/p/great-newspapers-and-the-problem?utm_campaign=post</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 17:49:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prejudice and misconduct remain in Massachusetts high school sports — but the MIAA won’t say where - The Boston Globe</title><link>https://www.bostonglobe.com/2023/06/16/sports/massachusetts-high-school-sports-bias-incidents/</link><description>A disturbing pattern of discriminatory acts persists across the state, according to a new tracking system. But the MIAA isn't interested in sharing details.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 16:08:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How our weak public records law is enabling a cover-up of school sports harassment</title><link>https://dankennedy.net/2023/06/20/how-our-weak-public-records-law-is-enabling-a-cover-up-of-school-sports-harassment/</link><description>Sports builds character, we are told over and over again. And yet Massachusetts has been hit with multiple cases of racist, homophobic harassment aimed at high school athletes. 🗽The New England Muz…</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 15:48:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Not Your Dad’s Dad Food</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/13/dining/fathers-day-dad-food.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 17:47:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daniel Ellsberg, Who Leaked the Pentagon Papers, Is Dead at 92</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/16/us/daniel-ellsberg-dead.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 18:57:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opinion | This Father’s Day, stop treating dads as dopes, deadbeats or icebergs</title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/06/15/fathers-day-paid-leave-diapers/</link><description>Paid leave. Postpartum mental health care. Equal access to changing tables. Help providing. Men deserve family policy just as much as women do.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 16:38:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Urban exodus: Maps show where people across the U.S. are moving</title><link>https://www.sfchronicle.com/projects/2023/maps-migration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 12:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Instant Pot Failed Because It Was a Good Product</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2023/06/instant-pot-bankrupt-private-equity/674414/</link><description>A one-hit wonder is never enough.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 02:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United States of America v. Donald J. Trump and Waltine Nauta</title><link>https://www.lawfareblog.com/united-states-america-v-donald-j-trump-and-waltine-nauta</link><description>The former president faces federal charges for the first time in the Mar-a-Lago case.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 01:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opinion | 758 doctors for 19 million kids. The safety net for kids is gone.</title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/06/06/early-intervention-special-education-psychologist/</link><description>Backlogs for early intervention services are months long. 25 states have critical shortages of special education teachers. What's a parent to do?</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 15:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>It's infuriatingly hard to understand how closed models train on their input</title><link>http://simonwillison.net/2023/Jun/4/closed-model-training/#atom-entries</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 13:11:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to Prepare for Wildfire Smoke, According to Doctors at Harvard</title><link>https://heatmap.news/climate/wildfire-smoke-health-effects-breathing</link><description>Experts explain what you can do about the smoke engulfing the East Coast and Midwest.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:44:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Analysis | America’s doughnut capital. Can we stop at just one? </title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2023/06/02/donut-capital-america/</link><description>No country loves fried dough more than the United States. But is America split by a hidden doughnut divide? We investigate.  </description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 16:59:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Murder Rate Is Suddenly Falling</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2023/06/us-murder-rate-decline-crime-statistics/674290/</link><description>The first five months of 2023 have produced an encouraging overall trend for the first time in years.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 17:58:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supreme Risk: An Interactive Guide to Rights the Supreme Court Could Take Away</title><link>https://projects.propublica.org/supreme-risk/</link><description>Most rights are based in statute, but dozens — such as rights to same-sex marriage, search warrants and Miranda warnings — are based on judicial rulings that the Supreme Court can overturn and that current justices have questioned some aspect of.</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 11:52:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists at country’s largest newspaper chain will walk off the job</title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/media/2023/06/01/gannett-journalist-strike-walkout-protest-ceo/</link><description>Hundreds of staffers at Gannett newspapers across seven states are protesting their company’s leadership and job cuts.</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 13:11:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pork-pocalypse now? In wake of Supreme Court ruling and 2016 vote, pork prices could soar in Mass. - The Boston Globe</title><link>https://www.bostonglobe.com/2023/05/27/business/pork-pocalypse-now-wake-supreme-court-ruling-2016-vote-pork-prices-could-soar-mass/</link><description>A 2016 animal welfare ballot measure that would prohibit most US pork from being sold in Massachusetts could finally take effect as soon as next month. And pork purveyors here say that means prices are about to pop.</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 23:23:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From the editor: Sonoma County trans student-athlete’s story is not ours to tell</title><link>https://www.pressdemocrat.com/article/news/from-the-editor-sonoma-county-trans-student-athletes-story-is-not-ours-to/</link><description>The national firestorm that ignited last week over a Sonoma County transgender student-athlete is bullying, plain and simple, says Richard A. Green, executive editor of The Press Democrat.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 20:12:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As wildfire smoke worsens public health, government watchdog calls EPA response 'ad hoc'</title><link>https://www.muckrock.com/news/archives/2023/may/23/wildfire-smoke-exceptional-event/</link><description>Congressional investigators say the use of a regulatory loophole to erase smoke pollution from the official record is on the rise.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 14:14:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gannett is experiencing a mass exodus among top execs. Here’s who has left. - Poynter</title><link>https://www.poynter.org/business-work/2023/gannett-is-experiencing-a-mass-exodus-among-top-execs-heres-who-has-left/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 12:54:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>