<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Chris Amico, journalist &amp; programmer: Links</title><link>https://chrisamico.com</link><description>Journalist &amp; programmer</description><atom:link href="https://chrisamico.com" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 12:12:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Elon Musk’s X is throttling traffic to websites he dislikes </title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2023/08/15/twitter-x-links-delayed/</link><description>The delayed websites include X’s online rivals Facebook, Instagram, Bluesky and Substack as well as Reuters and the New York Times, all of which Musk previously has singled out for ridicule or attack.</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 18:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Judge rules in favor of Montana youths in landmark climate decision</title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2023/08/14/youths-win-montana-climate-trial/</link><description>“This is a monumental decision," said a lawyer for the young plaintiffs, and could influence similar cases in other states. </description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 17:23:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Antitrust suit vs. UFC granted class certification</title><link>https://www.espn.com/mma/ufc/story/_/id/38163830/antitrust-suit-ufc-officially-granted-class-certification</link><description>A federal judge in Nevada granted class certification to plaintiffs in an antitrust lawsuit filed against the UFC. Nearly 1,200 fighters can now sue the UFC as a collective for alleged unfair business practices.</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 22:55:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The other greenhouse gas</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/graphics/FOOD-WASTE/METHANE/gdpzwqwqovw/</link><description>How methane from food waste contributes to global warming and why small efforts to stop it can make a big difference.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 15:20:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Emerging Science of Tracing Smoke Back to Wildfires</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/28/climate/tracing-wildfire-smoke-health.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 15:35:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The affordance loop - Erin Kissane's small internet website</title><link>https://erinkissane.com/the-affordance-loop</link><description>The stiltwalking French shepherds in the marshes of the Landes are incredible, and I love this postcard—which you can buy from a nice person on</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 12:50:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charles Ogletree, Harvard Law professor who mentored the Obamas, dies at 70 - The Boston Globe</title><link>https://www.bostonglobe.com/2023/08/04/metro/charles-ogletree-harvard-law-professor-who-mentored-obamas-dies-70/</link><description>A towering figure in civil rights and the legal community, Mr. Ogletree mentored Barack and Michelle Obama when they were Harvard Law School students, and represented famous clients in court.</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 11:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Big One: Trump Is Indicted for Jan. 6</title><link>https://www.lawfaremedia.org/article/the-big-one-trump-is-indicted-for-jan.-6</link><description>Donald Trump faces accountability for his grandest crime. </description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 15:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. v. Trump Will Be the Most Important Case in Our Nation’s History</title><link>https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2023/08/trump-trial-2024-historic-jack-smith-indictment.html</link><description>It is perhaps the most important indictment ever handed down to safeguard American democracy and the rule of law in any U.S. court against anyone.</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:39:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Canada’s Record Wildfires Got So Bad, So Fast</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2023/07/18/climate/canada-record-wildfires.html</link><description>Blazes have burned 25 million acres so far this year, and there’s still a month to go in peak fire season.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 18:37:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 Common Angles Data Journalists Use to Tell Stories</title><link>https://gijn.org/2023/07/13/4-common-angles-data-journalists-tell-stories/?mc_cid=9f07655d8c&amp;mc_eid=deb869554c</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 17:13:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Read the thousands of documents journalists used to investigate St. Louis radioactive waste • Missouri Independent</title><link>https://missouriindependent.com/2023/07/19/read-the-thousands-of-documents-journalists-used-to-investigate-st-louis-radioactive-waste/</link><description>MuckRock and The Missouri Independent are making all of the government documents it obtained as part of its “Atomic Fallout” investigation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 19:20:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cambridge schools are divided over middle school algebra - The Boston Globe</title><link>https://www.bostonglobe.com/2023/07/14/metro/cambridge-schools-divided-over-middle-school-math/</link><description>The district’s aim in eliminating advanced math in middle school was to reduce disparities between low-income children of color and their more affluent peers. But some argue the decision has had the opposite effect.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 16:20:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How a Vast Demographic Shift Will Reshape the World</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2023/07/16/world/world-demographics.html</link><description>The most powerful countries have benefited from large work forces for decades. What happens when they retire?</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 13:08:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exclusive: AP strikes news-sharing and tech deal with OpenAI</title><link>https://www.axios.com/2023/07/13/ap-openai-news-sharing-tech-deal</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 20:27:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Red Sox, Massachusetts</title><link>https://bostonography.com/2023/red-sox-massachusetts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 19:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Atomic Fallout’: Records reveal government downplayed, ignored health risks of St. Louis radioactive waste for decades</title><link>https://www.muckrock.com/news/archives/2023/jul/12/st-louis-landfill-toxic-superfund/</link><description>The Missouri Independent, MuckRock and The Associated Press spent months combing through thousands of pages of previously-unreleased government records obtained through the Freedom of Information Act that show radioactive waste was known to pose a threat to people living near Coldwater Creek as early as 1949. But federal officials repeatedly wrote potential risks off as ‘slight,’ ‘minimal’ or ‘low-level.’</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 15:35:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opinion | For Most College Students, Affirmative Action Was Never Enough</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2023/07/03/opinion/for-most-college-students-affirmative-action-was-not-enough.html</link><description>The loss of affirmative action is an opportunity to refocus on supporting middle- and lower-tiered colleges.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 13:12:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The grass courts are now in session</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/graphics/TENNIS-WIMBLEDON/GRAPHIC/lbvggkzjmvq/</link><description>Wimbledon is the only grass court Grand Slam</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 12:35:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Texas Barbecue Is the Best It Has Ever Been. Here’s Why.</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/03/dining/texas-bbq.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 15:15:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>